Before we get started making recommendations,
在开始创建推荐之前
it's important we have a good understanding of
我们需要充分了解
the data we'll be working with in the next couple of lessons.
将在接下来的几节课中用到的数据
In this notebook, we'll explore the data and answer a few questions.
在此 notebook 中 我们将探索数据并回答几个问题
To get started, we'll read in the data.
首先 我们将读取数据
So you can see we have two data sets,
有两个数据集
one is the movies data set and it looks like it has three columns.
一个是 movies 数据集 它有三列
One with the movie id, one with movie name,
一列是 movie_id 一列是 movie
and one with a genre.
一列 genre
The genre has multiple possible categories and also potentially NaNs.
genre 列有多个可能的类别 并且可能是 NaN
If we look at the reviews,
再看看 reviews 数据集
it has a user id,
它有一个 user_id
a movie id which I imagine matches the movies data set for their movie id column,
一个 movie_id 我猜测它与 movies 数据集的 movie_id 列相匹配
a rating user gave to this movie, and a timestamp.
一个 rating 表示用户对此电影的评分 还有一个 timestamp
A couple of the questions that are down here
下面有几个问题
says to find the number of movies in the dataset,
其中一个是查找数据集中的电影数量
so we can get the movies from just the movies.shape zero.
输入 movies.shape[0]
So, it looks like we have, in my case,
我这边显示有 31,917 部电影
31,917 but your dataset
但是你的数据集可能数量不同
again might have a different number depending on when you're running this notebook.
取决于你是何时运行此 notebook 的
Again, these are live pulling from a constantly updated MovieTweetings dataset.
我们实时地从不断更新的 MovieTweetings 数据集中提取数据
The number of readings we can get from the reviews shapes
评分数量可以通过 reviews.shapes[0] 获取
zero and so there are a lot of them.
评分数量很多
The number of different genres.
不同风格的数量
So this is a little tricky because what we want to do is
这个问题比较难
if we look again at the movies data set,
再看看 movies 数据集
what we want to be able to do is pull these parts out of those genre portion.
我们要做的是能够从 genre 中提取这些部分
We can write a little loop to do this.
我们可以编写一个小循环
I'll create an empty list genres and basically
我将创建一个空的列表 叫做 genres
what we'll do is we'll loop through that column,
然后遍历该列
there are probably lots of ways you could do this, this is one.
提取方法可能有很多种 这只是其中一种方法
So, I'm going to loop through this column and I'm going to do this as a try,
我将遍历此列并将这段代码放入 try-except 块中
except because if I hit one of those NaNs,
因为如果遇到 NaN
I think I will get an attribute error.
则会出现属性错误
I'm just going to pass if I hit a NaN.
如果遇到 NaN 则 pass
Otherwise, what I want to do is I want to pull.
否则提取数据
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to split this.
我将拆分这部分
So, if we can actually just look at what this does,
看看代码的作用
so if we take movies genre zero and we run a split on that,
输入 movies.genre[0] 对其运行 split()
the idea is it's going to give me this list of these things.
系统将返回这些部分组成的列表
So, what we can do,
我们可以
is we can just loop through each of these, which,
遍历这些项目
again it's going to take a little bit of time because
运行需要花点时间
there's 31,000 of them but it shouldn't be too bad.
因为有 31,000 多个 但是不会太久
So, I'm going to loop through, I'm going to extend this list and then the number of genre
我将遍历一遍并扩展此列表
should actually just be the set of this.
风格数量等于 len(set(genres))
We can get the names of those two.
还可以获取这些风格的名称
So, it looks like there's 28 of them, so we do it like this.
有 28 种 这些是所有的风格名称
Yeah. So, it looks like there's 28 and here's a list of them.
Yeah有 28 种 这些是名称列表
Again, there's probably a better way to potentially do
重申下 可能有更好的实现方式
this but this is one potential method that works,
这只是其中一种可行的方式
it's just looping through all of the possibilities,
我只是遍历所有的可能性
splitting based on this, creating a list,
拆分项目 创建列表
and then extending our original list by that,
然后扩展原始列表
and then at the end we just take a set to get only the unique items.
最后使用 set() 获取唯一项
So, the next one is getting the unique number of users.
下个问题是获取唯一用户数量
So, there's an MP unique and we can run that on the reviews,
输入 np.unique 对 reviews 数据集运行该方法
it's just user one.
这是第一个用户
User id.
用户 ID
Okay. So, in
Ok在我的数据集中
my particular dataset I have 54,000,
有 54,000 个唯一用户
the number of missing ratings under reviews dataset.
下个问题是 reviews 数据集中缺少的评分数量
So, for that, we can do reviews.reading.
输入 reviews.rating
Great. Then we're going to do is null and
Great然后输入 isnull().sum()
then some- yeah so it doesn't look like there's any missing ratings.
看起来没有缺少任何评分
The average rating given looks like it's 7.3.
平均评分为 7.3 分
We can actually do a whole bunch of stats.
实际上可以查看很多统计数据
So the min is zero,
最低分为 0 分
then max is 10.
最高分为 10 分
There's a couple of other useful pieces of information,
还有很多其他有用的信息
the median, the 25th percentile, the 75th percentile.
例如均值 第 25 百分位 第 75 百分位